# **Archie Dobiss**

London archie.dobiss@gmail.com +44 7917 332892

As an entry-level data scientist and experienced data analyst, I write scripts to clean, map and algorithmically extract vital data from large datasets with high accuracy to make automated decisions using Python, Jupyter Notebook and SQL. Dedicated to lifelong learning, I successfully completed an AI Bootcamp at the University of Huddersfield and currently study calculus. Passionate about utilising my technical and problem-solving abilities, I enjoy tackling complex problems and contributing to organisational growth. My goal is to build career as a Data Scientist (ML).

- Algorithmically extracted vital metadata for 100k+ onboarded copyrights even though the Tech department said it was impossible thus reducing manual workload by 40%
- Wrote a suspense royalty metadata mapping script using SQL and matched over £500k worth of previously unallocated royalties
- Created secure XGBoost spam filter without any spam filter tutorials (92% precision, 99% recall)
- Kobalt Hackathon 2019 End User Impact award-winning team (Machine learning model for musical composition recognition using metadata).

# Work Experience

### **Software Engineer (Music Intelligence)**

SoundCloud - London July 2022 to March 2023

- Advised on and troubleshot Music AI API endpoint integration
- Identified main onboarding issues for each of the Music AI API products and provided solutions
- Prepared onboarding collaterals
- Documented Music AI product specs
- Wrote API wrappers in Python

### **Freelance Software Engineer**

Musiio Ltd. - Remote

August 2021 to November 2021

- Assisted Musiio with Al Music Classification via API for prospective clients
- Debugged API wrappers and wrote supporting Python scripts
- Labelled training datasets for new classifiers

#### Royalties Analyst/ Distribution Manager

Kobalt Music Publishing - London July 2013 to July 2020

- Proactively identified, suggested and managed to completion metadata mapping algorithm improvements
- Responsible for maintaining and improving existing as well as creating new source-to-target mappings for all data sources

- Wrote custom SQL reports to analyse imported royalty files to make sure the data was delivered and ingested accordingly and investigated if otherwise
- Resolved data conflicts and established sources of truth
- Added new data ingestion features based on support ticket analysis
- · Created and provided training, Maintained and updated internal Wiki obo the team
- Successful task prioritisation and re-prioritisation in high workload volume and hard deadline environment.

### Education

## **Bootcamp in Artificial Intelligence Bootcamp**

University of Huddersfield

November 2021 to March 2022

#### Skills

- International data standard implementation (5 years)
- Problem solving (5 years)
- Classification, Feature extraction, Dimensionality reduction, K-fold validation, Testing
- RESTful web services (2 years)
- Digital collaboration (via Git)
- AWS Cloud Practitioner course (in-progress).
- Operational planning, Project management (6 years)
- Python, Jupyter Notebook (2 years)
- Scikit-learn, TensorFlow
- Finding errors in data, Applying short and long-term solutions (6 years)
- Data analysis (EDA), SQL, Relational databases (5 years)

#### Links

github.com/adobiss

linkedin.com/in/adobiss